Dorothy Kenyon Papers, 1850-1998
Sophia Smith Collection, Smith College
- SERIES VI. ACTIVITIES AND ORGANIZATIONS (1923-1971), 15.0 linear feet
  This series--by far the largest one in the collection--documents the wide range of Kenyon's political and professional interests and activities from the 1920s through 1971. Throughout these five decades Kenyon participated in a vast number of social movements including labor, women's rights, civil liberties, civil rights, international human rights, and the fight against poverty. As a proponent of these causes she was active in scores of organizations that covered the spectrum from radical to liberal. Because of her liberal record and her political skill and effectiveness Kenyon was appointed to highly regarded positions as the U.S. delegate to the League of Nations Committee to Study the Legal Status of Women in 1937 and the United Nations Commission on the Status of Women in 1947. For the same reasons she also had to mount a major defense of her political history and reputation after she was targeted by Senator Joseph McCarthy in 1950. The League of Nations, the United Nations, and the McCarthy Hearings--each containing correspondence, committee files, internal memoranda, publications, reports, and research files--represent some of the most important segments of this series. The series is arranged alphabetically by the name of the activity or organization.
  The largest amount of material in this series--next to the League of Nations, the McCarthy hearings, and the United Nations--relates to Kenyon's work in the American Civil Liberties Union; to her central role in Chilmark Associates, which managed the Barn House cooperative on Martha's Vineyard; and to her participation in community development activities on the Lower West Side of Manhattan. The ACLU material includes correspondence, committee files, conference programs, newspaper clippings, and research files on issues addressed by the organization such as abortion, race exclusion, sex discrimination, and free speech. Legal cases Kenyon prepared for the ACLU are located in SERIES V. LEGAL PRACTICE. The Chilmark Associates files contain correspondence among members, legal and financial documents, meeting minutes, and reports. Lower West Side Community Development Activities serves as the heading for the large number of organizations that comprised Kenyon's work in the War on Poverty in the 1960s. This material is quite rich and contains correspondence, committee files, minutes, memoranda, proposals, publicity, reports, and financial data for groups such as the Community Corporation of the Lower West Side and Mobilization for Youth. Other major organizations represented in this series include the American Labor Party, Americans for Democratic Action, League for Mutual Aid, the NAACP Legal Defense and Educational Fund, and the Women's Strike Coalition.
- SERIES VII. SUBJECTS (1925-1971), .4 linear feet
  This series is arranged alphabetically by subject and includes topics in which Kenyon had a particular interest including abortion, anti-communism, civil rights, conscription of women into the armed forces, the Equal Rights Amendment, jury service for women, the status of women, and the Supreme Court, among others. It appears that Kenyon kept these files in order to save and organize information that she might later use in her speeches and articles. Some of them, such as the file on the Equal Rights Amendment, consist of a variety of material that was clearly gathered over several decades. Others, such as the file on Richard Nixon contain only one item. Types of material included in this series include articles, newspaper clippings, notes, writings by others, and miscellaneous printed material.
- SERIES VIII. PHOTOGRAPHS (1888-1971), .75 linear feet
  This series, consists primarily of black-and-white photographic prints. It is arranged in the following subseries: Personal and family; Formal portraits of Kenyon alone; Kenyon in professional settings with groups; Kenyon in her United Nations Work; Kenyon at the McCarthy hearings; and Kenyon receiving honors. The series also includes an album compiled by Kenyon's cousin Katherine Wilby that contains photos of Kenyon's and Wilby's European tour in 1908 and numerous photos of the Kenyon and Wilby families during the years between 1900-1910. See also SERIES X. OVERSIZE MATERIALS
- SERIES IX. AUDIOVISUAL MATERIAL (1948-1998), .25 linear feet
  This series consists solely of audiotapes and is arranged in two subseries: Events and Interviews. Events includes recordings of events in which Kenyon participated, including her testimony before the Tydings Senate Foreign Relations Committee in response to McCarthy's charges (1950), and her 80th birthday party (1968). Other MATERIAL relating to these events can be found in SERIES I. BIOGRAPHICAL MATERIAL--Tributes and Testimonials; SERIES VI. ACTIVITIES AND ORGANIZATIONS--McCarthy Hearings; and SERIES IX. PHOTOGRAPHS. Interviews includes interviews with Kenyon as well as interviews with others about her. Two of the three interviews with Kenyon focus on her work with the United Nations in the late 1940s; the third was conducted by Jacqueline Van Voris in 1971 as part of the Smith College Centennial Study. The interviews about Kenyon are some of the most recent additions to the collection. These came from Louise Wilby Knight (granddaughter of Kenyon's first cousin Katherine Curtis Wilby) who interviewed her mother, Frances Berna Knight, in 1997 and Kenyon's nephew, Tipton Kenyon, in 1998. There is a transcript of the Van Voris interview with Kenyon in SERIES I. BIOGRAPHICAL MATERIAL--Interviews. Additional MATERIAL relating to Tipton Kenyon and Louise Wilby Knight can be found in SERIES II.--Family.
- SERIES X. OVERSIZE MATERIAL (1938-1950), .25 linear feet
  This series includes items too large to be contained in regular archival boxes including certificates and a diploma (see also SERIES I. BIOGRAPHICAL MATERIAL and SERIES IX. PHOTOGRAPHS]; a photograph of a League of Nations function [see also SERIES VI. ACTIVITIES AND ORGANIZATIONS--League of Nations and SERIES IX. PHOTOGRAPHS]; a framed cartoon by Herblock depicting Kenyon's response to McCarthy [see also SERIES VI. ACTIVITIES AND ORGANIZATIONS--McCarthy Hearings], and and oversized LP containing an interview with Kenyon about her work with the United Nations Commission on the Status of Women [see also SERIES VI. ACTIVITIES AND ORGANIZATIONS--United Nations, and SERIES IX. AUDIOVISUAL MATERIAL--Interviews].
- SERIES I. BIOGRAPHICAL MATERIAL (1888-1980)
  - Writings about Kenyon
    - Short biographies, 1935-72, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Resumes, 1950-71, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Autobiographical notes and anecdotes, 1970, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Newspaper clippings about DK, 1924-73, n.d.
      - 1924-49 (Box 1, Folder 4-17)
      - 1950-73, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 1-17)
    - Material collected by Mildred Adams Kenyon for biography of DK: (Box 3, Folder 1-19)
    - correspondence, notes, drafts of chapters 1-7 (Box 4, Folder 1-5)
    - Scholarly article about Kenyon: Susan M. Hartmann, "The Odyssey of a Feminist: Dorothy Kenyon's Career," 1980 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Interviews, [see also SERIES IX. AUDIOVISUAL MATERIAL]
    - Transcript of radio interview with Miss Martin, 1939 (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - Interview with Vivian Lee Rutes in Smith College Alumnae Quarterly, 1940 (Box 4)
    - Transcript of radio interview with Dana C. Backus, 1940 (Box 4)
    - Transcript of interview re: UN Commission on the Status of Women, 1947 (Box 4)
    - Smith Centennial interview with J. Van Voris: transcript, 1971-72, [see also SERIES IX. AUDIOVISUAL MATERIAL] (Box 4)
    - Interview [fragment] with Miss Craig, n.d. (Box 4)
  - Tributes and testimonials
    - Party for Kenyon and other members of the UN Commission on the Status of Women: correspondence (including notes from E. Roosevelt and Frieda Miller) and lists, 1947 (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - Kenyon-United Nations dinner upon her return from Beirut: correspondence (including notes from E. Roosevelt, Molly Dewson, Frances Perkins), invitation, and lists, 1949 (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - Dinner for Kenyon's birthday: correspondence (including notes from Roger Baldwin, E. Roosevelt, Frieda Miller) and lists, 1953 (Box 4, Folder 10)
    - Testimonial Dinner in honor of Kenyon's 80th birthday, 1968, [see also SERIES IX. AUDIOVISUAL MATERIAL]
      - Planning: correspondence and lists, 1967-68 (Box 4, Folder 11)
      - Birthday greetings (includes Max Eastman, Hubert Humphrey, and Robert Kennedy), 1968 (Box 4, Folder 12)
      - Memorabilia: invitation, newspaper clippings, notes, program, and speeches, 1968 (Box 4, Folder 13)
      - Thank you notes, 1968 (Box 4, Folder 14)
    - Welcome Home Party after hospitalization: correspondence and lists, Feb 1970 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Education: correspondence, grade reports, and commencement programs, 1904-1917 (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Awards and citations, 1948-71, n.d., [see also SERIES VIII. PHOTOGRAPHS] (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Honorary degrees: diplomas, nominations and programs, 1939-66, [see also SERIES VIII. PHOTOGRAPHS and SERIES X. OVERSIZE MATERIAL] (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - Memberships: cards, certificates, and lists, 1944-71 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Legal documents: passports, driver's licenses, wills, and inventory of DK's estate, 1923-67 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Financial documents
    - Tax records, 1921-70
      - Individual: lists, notes, worksheets, completed forms IRS and New York State Finance Administration forms
        - 1921-56 (Box 5, Folder 3-7)
        - 1957-70 (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - Business: worksheets and forms, 1937-1970 (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - Income and expense records
      - General, 1927-62 (Box 6, Folder 3)
      - U.N. salary receipts, 1949 (Box 6, Folder 4)
      - Income from Dorothy Kenyon Trust, 1971 (Box 6, Folder 5)
      - Loans, 1925-40 (Box 6, Folder 6)
      - Investments, 1921-38, 1965 (Box 6, Folder 7)
      - Contributions, 1958-71, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 8)
      - Cosmopolitan Club receipts, 1949-71 (Box 6, Folder 9)
      - Miscellaneous: lists and receipts, 1948-71, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 10)
      - Payroll account book, 1956-60 (Box 6, Folder 11)
      - Petty cash account book, Jan 1959--Apr 1970 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Contacts: address book and lists, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Calendar, 1965 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Professional credentials: certificates and references, 1936-50, [see also SERIES X. OVERSIZE MATERIAL] (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Funeral records: correspondence, guest list, program, obituaries, and transcript of Pauli Murray's eulogy, 1972, [see also SERIES II. FAMILY] (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Memorabilia, [see also SERIES VIII. PHOTOGRAPHS]
    - Baby book, 1888-89 (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - Correspondence from family on the occasion of Kenyon's birth, 1888 (Box 7, Folder 6-9)
    - Miscellaneous: childhood writings, cards, and printed matter, 1888-1960s, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 10-11)
    - Campaign poster, 1939, [see also SERIES X. OVERSIZE MATERIAL--Flat file] (Box 7, Folder 12)
    - FBI file, 1949-64 (Box 7A, Folder 1-3)
- SERIES II. FAMILY (1850-1998)
  - Kenyon's family tree (maternal line), 1998 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Individuals, [see also SERIES VIII. PHOTOGRAPHS]
    - Edward Tipton "Tip" Kenyon (Kenyon's nephew) and his wife Kit: correspondence, and eulogy for Theodore Kenyon, 1964-78 (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - Lestra Kinney Kenyon (William Houston Kenyon Sr.'s second wife and Kenyon's stepmother)
      - Correspondence, 1907-66, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 3)
      - Probate matters: correspondence and will, 1965-67 (Box 8, Folder 4)
    - Maria Wellington Stanwood "Minnie" Kenyon (William Houston Kenyon Sr.'s first wife and Kenyon's mother): correspondence, 1902 (Box 8, Folder 5)
    - Mary "Mamie" Kenyon (William Houston Kenyon Sr.'s sister): correspondence and obituary, 1903-50 (Box 8, Folder 6)
    - Mildred Adams Kenyon (William Houston Kenyon Jr.'s wife): correspondence, newspaper clippings, and wedding announcement, 1935-75, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 7-9)
    - Theodore Stanwood "T.O." Kenyon and wives Helen and Sally (Kenyon's brother and sisters-in-law): correspondence, 1903-72, [see also SERIES IX. AUDIOVISUAL MATERIAL] (Box 8, Folder 10-12)
    - Theodore Stanwood "Tat" Kenyon Jr. (Kenyon's nephew): correspondence, newspaper clippings, and program, 1938-71, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 13)
    - William Houston Kenyon Sr. (Kenyon's father)
      - Account book, 1881-1929 (Box 9, Folder 1)
      - Autograph book, 1876 (Box 9, Folder 2)
      - Bridal book from 1887 marriage to Maria Stanwood, [see SERIES X. OVERSIZE MATERIAL] (Box 9, Folder 3)
      - Compositions, photos, and letters, 1872-74, 1884 (Box 9, Folder 4)
      - Correspondence, 1876-1930
        - Letters from abroad, 1889 (Box 9, Folder 5)
        - Letters describing trip to Europe, 1892 (Box 9, Folder 6)
        - Letters to family, 1876-1930 (Box 9, Folder 7)
      - Diary, 1874 (Box 9, Folder 8)
    - William Houston "Houtie" Kenyon Jr. (Kenyon's brother): correspondence, 1905-73 (Box 10, Folder 1-3)
    - J.P. McGavin to A.B. Houston: correspondence, 1850 (Box 10, Folder 4)
    - Louise Wilby Knight (granddaughter of Kenyon's first cousin Katherine Curtis Wilby): correspondence (including letters to and from Gloria Steinem), 1987-92, [see also SERIES IX. AUDIOVISUAL MATERIAL] (Box 10, Folder 5)
    - Clara Kinney Shields, (Kenyon's step-aunt): correspondence, 1950-70, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 6)
    - Mary Stanwood Berna Till (daughter of Kenyon's first cousin Katherine Curtis Wilby): correspondence with Louise Wilby Knight, 1987 (Box 10, Folder 7)
    - Miscellaneous family members: correspondence and newspaper clippings, 1887-1969, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - Special events
    - Family trip to Canadian Rockies: arrangements, correspondence, diary, and maps, 1969 (Box 10, Folder 9)
    - Marriage of William Houston Kenyon Sr. to Lestra Kinney: correspondence and invitation, 1909 (Box 10, Folder 10)
- SERIES III. CORRESPONDENCE (1917-1971)
  - General, 1918-72, n.d.
    - 1918-Mar 1950 (Box 11, Folder 1-9)
    - Apr 1950-64 (Box 12, Folder 1-10)
    - 1965-Feb 1968 (Box 13, Folder 1-9)
    - Mar 1986-71 (Box 14, Folder 1-15)
    - 1971, n.d. (Box 15, Folder 1-2)
  - Friends and associates
    - Abzug, Bella, 1970, [see also SERIES VI. ACTIVITIES AND ORGANIZATIONS] (Box 15, Folder 3)
    - Allen, Florence, 1964 (Box 15, Folder 4)
    - Atkinson, Ti Grace, [see also SERIES VI. ACTIVITIES AND ORGANIZATIONS] (Box 15)
    - Baldwin, Roger, 1963, n.d., [see also SERIES VI. ACTIVITIES AND ORGANIZATIONS] (Box 15, Folder 5)
    - Bethune, Mary McLeod, [see SERIES VI. ACTIVITIES AND ORGANIZATIONS--UN Commission on the Status of Women] (Box 15)
    - Bird, Caroline, 1971 (Box 15, Folder 6)
    - Clarenbach, Kathryn, 1966 (Box 15, Folder 7)
    - Deming, Barbara, 1964 (Box 15, Folder 8)
    - Dershowitz, Alan, 1971 (Box 15, Folder 9)
    - Dewson, Mollie, 1950 (Box 15, Folder 10)
    - Douglas, Helen Gaghan, 1950 (Box 15, Folder 11)
    - Draper, Muriel, 1950 (Box 15, Folder 12)
    - Edwards, India, 1950 (Box 15, Folder 13)
    - Frankfurter, Felix, 1919 (Box 15, Folder 14)
    - Friedan, Betty, [see SERIES VI. ACTIVITIES AND ORGANIZATIONS--National Organization for Women and Women's Strike for Equality] (Box 15)
    - Glasser, Ira, 1970 (Box 15, Folder 15)
    - Goodell, Charles, 1970 (Box 15, Folder 16)
    - Height, Dorothy, 1965 (Box 15, Folder 17)
    - Hernandez, Aileen, [see SERIES VI. ACTIVITIES AND ORGANIZATIONS--National Organization for Women and Women's Strike for Equality] (Box 15)
    - Humphrey, Hubert, 1954,1964, 1968, 1971 (Box 15, Folder 18)
    - Hutchins, Grace, 1964 (Box 15, Folder 19)
    - Javits, Jacob, 1970 (Box 15, Folder 20)
    - Kennedy, Robert F., 1966 (Box 15, Folder 21)
    - Keyserling, Leon, [see SERIES VI. ACTIVITIES AND ORGANIZATIONS] (Box 15)
    - Keyserling, Mary, 1964 (Box 15, Folder 22)
    - King, Gertrude, 1920-1923 (Box 15, Folder 23-26)
    - Kirchway, Frieda, 1919 (Box 15, Folder 27)
    - King, Martin Luther Jr., [see SERIES VI. ACTIVITIES AND ORGANIZATIONS] (Box 15)
    - Koch, Edward, 1970, 1971 (Box 15, Folder 28)
    - La Follette, Suzanne, 1923 (Box 15, Folder 29)
    - LaGuardia, Fiorello, 1936 (Box 15, Folder 30)
    - Lamont, Corliss, 1950 (Box 15, Folder 31)
    - Lasky, Victor, 1950 (Box 15, Folder 32)
    - Lehman, Herbert, 1950 (Box 15, Folder 33)
    - Marks, Jeannette, 1950 (Box 15, Folder 34)
    - McGovern, George, [see SERIES VI. ACTIVITIES AND ORGANIZATIONS] (Box 15)
    - Miller, Frieda, 1964 (Box 15, Folder 35)
    - Motley, Constance Baker, 1964-69, n.d., [see SERIES VI. ACTIVITIES AND ORGANIZATIONS] (Box 15, Folder 36)
    - Murray, Pauli, 1966 (Box 15, Folder 37)
    - Muskie, Edmund, 1969, 1971 (Box 15, Folder 38)
    - Myrdal, Alva, 1950 (Box 15, Folder 39)
    - Norton, Eleanor Holmes, 1970, 1971 (Box 15, Folder 40)
    - Palley, Marian Leif, 1965 (Box 15, Folder 41)
    - Pilpel, Harriet, 1964, 1965, 1971, [see SERIES VI. ACTIVITIES AND ORGANIZATIONS] (Box 15, Folder 42)
    - Pitkin, Mary, 1921 (Box 15, Folder 43)
    - Pitkin, Winifred, 1922 (Box 15, Folder 44)
    - Pitkin, Wolcott H., 1917-39 n.d., [see SERIES VI. ACTIVITIES AND ORGANIZATIONS-Chilmark]
      - 1917-20 (Box 15, Folder 45-49)
      - 1921-39, n.d. (Box 16, Folder 1-11)
    - Pulsifer, L.V., 1950-56, [see also SERIES VI. ACTIVITIES AND ORGANIZATIONS-Chilmark] (Box 16, Folder 12-18)
    - Randolph, A. Philip, [SEE SERIES VI. ACTIVITIES AND ORGANIZATIONS] (Box 16)
    - Roosevelt, Eleanor, 1950, [see also SERIES I. BIOGRAPHICAL MATERIAL--Tributes and Testimonials; SERIES VI. ACTIVITIES AND ORGANIZATIONS United Nations] (Box 16, Folder 19)
    - Root, Elihu, 1923-39, n.d.
      - 1923-24 (Box 16, Folder 20-23)
      - 1925-39, n.d. (Box 17, Folder 1-7)
    - Rosensohn, Samuel, 1919 (Box 17, Folder 8)
    - Rustin, Bayard, 1970, [see also SERIES VI. ACTIVITIES AND ORGANIZATIONS] (Box 17, Folder 9)
    - Schneiderman, Rose, 1950, 1968, 1971 (Box 17, Folder 10)
    - Steinem, Gloria, 1971 (Box 17, Folder 11)
    - Strauss, Anna Lord, 1950 (Box 17, Folder 12)
    - Thomas, Norman, 1963, 1966, [see also SERIES VI. ACTIVITIES AND ORGANIZATIONS] (Box 17, Folder 13)
    - Tobias, Sheila, 1970 (Box 17, Folder 14)
    - Truman, Harry S., 1950 (Box 17, Folder 15)
    - Tydings, Millard E., 1950 (Box 17, Folder 16)
    - Ware, Caroline, 1966 (Box 17, Folder 17)
    - Woodsmall, Ruth, [see also SERIES VI. ACTIVITIES AND ORGANIZATIONS] (Box 17)
    - Wright, Alice Morgan, 1950 (Box 17, Folder 18)
  - Letters to the Editor from Kenyon, 1948-1971 (Box 17, Folder 19)
- SERIES IV. SPEECHES AND WRITINGS (1925-1972)
  - Addresses & articles
    - Correspondence re: speeches and appearances, 1944-70
      - 1944-May 1950 (Box 17, Folder 20-26)
      - June 1950-70 (Box 18, Folder 1-5)
    - Manuscripts and typescripts, 1925-1972, n.d., >[see Appendix for list of articles and addresses by subject]
      - 1925-35 (Box 18, Folder 6-14)
      - 1936-40 (Box 19, Folder 1-10)
      - 1941-47 (Box 20, Folder 1-12)
      - 1948-53 (Box 21, Folder 1-11)
      - 1954-62 (Box 22, Folder 1-15)
      - 1963-72, n.d. (Box 23, Folder 1-9)
    - Book reviews
      - General, 1936-1951 (Box 23, Folder 10)
      - Lawrence Lader's book on abortion: correspondence and manuscript, 1966 (Box 23, Folder 11)
      - Police Power: Police Abuses in New York City by Paul Chivigny, Pantheon Books, 1968: correspondence and manuscript (Box 23, Folder 12)
    - Encyclopedia entries
      - "Law relating to Husband and Wife," typescript, n.d. (Box 23, Folder 13)
      - "Ten Eventful Years," Encyclopedia Britannica, 1946: correspondence, notes, and manuscript (Box 23, Folder 14)
      - "Woman Suffrage," Encyclopedia Americana, 1948, 1950, 1958, 1959: manuscripts and published entries (Box 23, Folder 15)
      - "Women in the World," Encyclopedia Americana, 1949-1965, 1971, n.d.: correspondence, manuscripts, and published entries (Box 23, Folder 16)
      - "Women's Liberation: The Equal Rights Amendment," Encyclopedia Americana, 1970-71: contract, correspondence, and manuscripts (Box 23, Folder 17)
  - Books
    - "A Comparative Study of Techniques in the Holding of Hearings in the Executive Departments of the New York City Government": manuscript, 1937 (Box 24, Folder 1)
    - Women Must Work (unpublished manuscript in progress), circa 1941-42 ? (Box 24, Folder 2)
      - Research material: articles, correspondence, newspaper clippings, notes, and printed matter, 1942-43 (Box 24, Folder 3-4)
      - Reader's report by Mildred Adams, 1942 (Box 24, Folder 5)
    - "What We Face Today," for Robert L. Carter, Dorothy Kenyon, Peter Marcuse, and Loren Miller, Equality, Pantheon Books, 1965: correspondence, draft, publicity, and reviews, 1964-65 (Box 24, Folder 6)
- SERIES V. LEGAL PRACTICE (1936-1969)
  - Clients and contacts
    - Lists of cases, clients, contracts, documents, papers (Box 24, Folder 7-8)
    - List of material in file, 1963-72 (Box 25, Folder 1)
  - Cases
    - W. Starling Burgess v. Boyd Donaldson, New York Supreme Court, Appellate Division (Box 25, Folder 2)
      - Papers on Appeal, 1936 (Box 25)
      - Brief for plaintiff-appellant (by Dorothy Straus and Dorothy Kenyon), 1937. (Box 25)
    - Rose Schneiderman v. King Features Syndicate, Inc., New York Supreme Court, Appellate Division: Papers on appeal by Dorothy Straus and Dorothy Kenyon, 1937 (Box 25, Folder 2)
    - Croton Estates, Inc. v. "John" Ruggiero, Municipal Court of the City of New York Borough of Manhattan, 3rd District: opinion, 1939 (Box 25)
    - People of the State of New York v. George Bohnke and Mrs. Henry T. (Eloise) Brown, NY State Court of Appeals: Amicus curiae briefs (by Dorothy Kenyon for ACLU), 1941 (Box 25)
    - Lester Follett v. Town of McCormick, SC, Supreme Court of the United States: motion and Amicus Curiae brief (by Dorothy Kenyon for ACLU), 1943 (Box 25)
    - Thelma Martin v. City of Struthers, Ohio, Supreme Court of the United States: Amicus curiae brief (by Dorothy Kenyon for American Civil Liberties Union), 1943 (Box 25)
    - The Case for Equality in State Jury Service: memorandum (by Dorothy Kenyon and Pauli Murray for ACLU) [in support of ACLU proposal to amend S. 2923 (Civil Rights Protection Act of 1966 )- -to deal with the exclusion of women from service on state juries], 1966 (Box 25, Folder 3)
    - Ida Philips v. Martin Marietta Corporation, Supreme Court of the United States: motion and Amicus curiae brief (by Dorothy Kenyon, Norman Dorsen, Pauli Murray, Melvin Wulf, Joel M. Gora for ACLU), 1969 (Box 25)
    - People of the State of New York v. Carmen Barber, New York State Court of Appeals: brief (by Committee on Civil Rights of the New York State Bar Association, The Committee on the Bill of Rights of the Association of the Bar of the City of New York, and the Committee on Civil Rights of the New York County Lawyers Association), n.d. (Box 25)
    - Paul J. Kern and Wallace Sayre v. Fiorello LaGuardia as Mayor, et al., New York Supreme Court, Appellate Division: Memorandum of Amici Curia (by Citizens Uinion of the City of New York, City Affairs Committee, Community Councils of the City of New York, New York City League of Women Voters, Women's City Club of New York), n.d. (Box 25, Folder 3)
  - Judicial Files, [see also SERIES VIII. PHOTOGRAPHS]
    - Jury charges, unidentified trials, n.d. (Box 25, Folder 4-7)
    - Outline of judge's role at a trial, unidentified trial, [on 4x6 index cards] (Box 25, Folder 8)
    - Opinion: Croton Estates, Inc. v. "John" Ruggiero, Municipal Court of the City of New York, Borough of Manhattan, 3rd District, 1939 (Box 25, Folder 9)
  - Research Files